(灵感源于真实事件)
凯瑟琳 你的名字蕴含柔和之意
Catherine. There is a softness in your name.
也许你不会顽强抵抗
Perhaps you will not be too much trouble.
跟我谈一谈 可以自救
You can help yourself by talking to me.
如果不谈的话
And if you don't...
我会伤害你
I will hurt you.
我会一直伤害你
And I will not stop to hurt you
直到你告诉我我想知道的一切
until you tell me everything.
七十二小时没休息了 你不想睡觉吗
Seventy-two hours without rest. Don't you want to sleep?
如果你不和我说话 折磨就永不停止
If you don't speak to me, this will never end.
有六名学生
There was a sixth student.
告诉我他们的名字 否则你就重回冰水里泡着
Tell me their name, or you're going back in the ice.
- 我没什么可告诉你的 - 不是
- I have nothing to say to you! - No...
不是...你现在安全了
No, no. You're safe.
你现在安全了 你回家了
You're safe. You're home.
不要这样 是我
No, it's me.
- 是我 我是克里斯汀 - 不要
- It's me. It's Christian. - Please!
新    风    貌
第一季第六集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
你告诉他们我正在提起诉讼 他们却什么都没说
So you told them I was suing, and they had nothing to say?
但你要明白你发起的是什么
But you need to understand what you have started here.
发起
Started?
我可没想着发起诉讼 我要毁了他们
I didn't start it. I'm going to ruin them.
- 可可... - 皮埃尔和保罗违反了我们签署的合同
- Coco-- - Pierre and Paul violated my contract
他们未经我的同意 就将香奈儿5号香水的生产转移到了美国
when they moved production of Chanel No. 5 to America without my consent.
背着我做的
Behind my back.
这要由法庭来决定
That's for a court to decide.
会涉及到进攻和反击 以及...
This will be attack and counterattack and--
该死的 雷奈 你是要做好自己的工作
Goddamn it, René. Are you going to do your job,
还是我得回去替你做
or do I have to come back home and do it for you?
我需要钱
I need money.
我安排了一场午餐 她们是瑞士最富有的女人
I have organized a lunch with the wealthiest women in Switzerland.
如果她们喜欢你 她们会付给你很多钱 让你给她们提供服装
If they like you, they will pay you a lot of money to dress them.
嗨 你好
Hi. Hello.
- 嗨 - 很高兴见到你
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
我也是
You too.
- 你好 很高兴见到你 - 你好 你好吗
- Hello. Nice to meet you. - Hello. How are you?
- 他们还没安排你们入座吗  - 还没
- Have they not seated you? - No, not yet.
不好意思 请帮我们都安排在我那桌
Sorry. Seat us all at my table, please.
没问题 小姐 我能跟你说句话吗
Certainly, mademoiselle. And may I have a quick word?
什么事
Yes?
小姐 你的账单...
Mademoiselle, your account--
我没时间讨论这个 我向你保证 我会支付的
I don't have time to discuss this. You have my word. I will pay.
请马上安排 这是一个很重要的午餐 让开
Please now, this is an important lunch. Step aside.
安德烈的身体状况如何
Tell me, how is André faring?
几天前 他和嘉贝拉已抵达巴黎 他的治疗已经开始了
He and Gabrielle arrived in Paris a few days ago. His treatment has begun.
希望一切顺利
Fingers crossed.
他们俩是我仅剩的亲人了
Those two are all I have left.
我爱他们胜过这个世界
I love them more than the world itself.
你有照片吗
Do you have a photo?
我孙子 孙女们的照片都在这
My grandchildren are here.
好可爱
How lovely.
有的 当然有 他们的肖像都裱起来了
Oh, yes. Yes, of course. Their portraits are getting framed.
我得问一下 那位女士是谁
I must ask, who is that lady?
哪位女士
What lady?
远处角落里的那个女人 从我们一坐下就一直盯着你
The woman in the far corner staring at you since we sat down.
可可 亲爱的 你好
Coco, darling. Hello.
- 她在向你招手 - 好久不见
- She's waving at you. - It's been too long.
她
Her?
亲爱的 可可 真不敢相信
Darling, Coco. I can't believe it.
- 可可... - 似乎还挺执着的
- Coco! Coco! - Seems insistent.
确实很执着 不是吗 是的
Yes, she is, isn't she? Yes.
大家都在看着 你最好过去打个招呼
Everyone's watching. You'd better go over and say hello.
凯瑟琳精疲力竭 还处于脱水状态
Catherine is dehydrated and exhausted.
你需要喂她简单的食物 因为她很可能得了溃疡
You need to feed her simple foods, because she most likely has ulcers.
好的 但还有别的方面出了问题
Okay, but there's-- Something else is wrong.
她常常不知道我是谁或她在哪里...
She often doesn't know who I am or where she is--
是的 但饥饿和营养不良 导致的影响是很复杂的
Yeah, but starvation and malnutrition, you know, the effects are complicated.
我们在那些从集中营回来的人身上 看到了多种症状
We're seeing multiple symptoms in those who have returned from the camps,
一些病历中 还有因创伤引起的健忘症
and in some cases, there is amnesia caused by trauma.
但她会恢复记忆吗
But her memory will return?
很有可能
Most likely.
不过重要的是不要逼她
Although it is essential that she'd not be pushed.
确保她好好休息
Make sure she rests.
迪奥先生
Monsieur Dior,
凯瑟琳遭受了极大的折磨
Catherine has suffered greatly.
饥饿能使人发疯
Starvation can drive people mad.
这种痛疼得让人难以忍受
It is an excruciating pain.
它不仅会造成身体伤害 还会造成头脑和精神伤害
It really damages the body but also the mind, the spirit.
我能做什么
What can I do?
给她点时间
Just give her time.
请一定要慢慢来
Take it slowly, please.
我每隔几天就会来看她
I'll check on her again every couple of days.
限制访客人数 可以的话 最好不要见客
Limit visitors. Best to have none if you can.
我不想让她看到我担心的样子
I don't want her to see me worried.
你现在得去见维格鲁了
You have your meeting with Vigouroux now.
我不能去 我不可能去的
I can't go. It's impossible.
这里有我照顾
I can manage here.
不行 早知她要回来 我决不会
No. I would never have made a leap if I'd have known
冒险创业 这是个奇迹
that she was going to return. It's a miracle.
是的
Yes, it is.
布萨克先生给你的这次机会也是一个奇迹
And Monsieur Boussac giving you this chance is also a miracle.
克里斯汀 不要浪费这次机会
Christian, don't waste it.
现在凯瑟琳回家了
Catherine is home now.
这才是最重要的事
That's the important thing.
你应该为自己感到骄傲
You should be proud of yourself.
你就去吧
So please go.
- 你必须做对你有利的事 - 知道了
- You must do what's good for you. - Yeah.
去吧
Go.
- 喂 - 请问这里是
- Hello. - Have I reached
克里斯汀迪奥家吗
the home of Christian Dior?
- 是的 这里是迪奥的住所 - 凯瑟琳回来了吗
- Yes. This is the Dior residence. - Has Catherine returned?
- 抱歉 凯瑟琳  - 对
- I'm sorry, Catherine? - Yes,
- 我想找她 麻烦了 - 不行 不可能的
- I would like to speak to her, please. - No, it's not possible.
- 你确定吗  - 不可以 抱歉
- Are you sure? - No, I'm sorry.
你绝不会相信 我离开马德里时遇到了多大的麻烦
You wouldn't believe the trouble I had getting out of Madrid.
英国大使馆的人
I mean, those people at the British Embassy,
他们所有人都只关心 我去过哪里 我知道什么
every one of them, all they cared about was where I'd been, what I knew.
问了我很多问题 真的累死人了
So many questions. It was really quite exhausting.
听起来很无聊
Sounds tedious.
无聊 不 这绝对是一种折磨
Tedious? No, it was absolute torture.
没错 但你毫发无损地离开了
Yes, well, you made it out in one piece.
这才是最重要的
That's all that matters.
你为什么在这里
Tell me, why are you here?
现在是午餐时间
It's lunchtime.
我本以为
I would have thought
伦敦会是你更想去的地方
that London would be a more desirable place for you to visit.
自我们在马德里的那次不幸事件后 我被贴上了叛徒的标签
Well, after our little tango in Madrid, I was labeled a traitor, you see.
我在英国的家人都和我断绝了关系
And my family in England, they all disowned me.
所以 现在我都听你的
So, now I'm all yours, you know.
我真走运
Lucky me.
告诉我这里怎么样
Tell me what it's like here.
所有的瑞士人似乎都很...
All these Swiss people seem so...
有钱
rich.
艾尔莎 别打坏主意
Don't get any ideas, Elsa.
什么主意
What ideas?
我正努力保持低调 你也应该这样
I'm trying to keep a low profile. You should as well.
现在还很危险
It's still dangerous.
法国政府是不是在追捕你
Is the French government after you?
小声点
Lower your voice.
抱歉
Sorry.
可可
Coco.
如果你想让我不透露我所知道的事
If you want me to keep quiet about what I know,
你为什么不确保我得到你承诺我的东西
why don't you just make sure I get what you promised me?
原来如此 就是为了钱
There it is. This is about money.
亲爱的 你在马德里说过 只是钱而已
Darling, you said it yourself in Madrid, it's just money.
当施帕茨把钱花光时 你就是这么跟我说的
That's what you told me when Spatz spent it all.
你说:“我可以给你更多的钱” 然后...
You said, "I can get more." And then--
你把我全心全意给予的灵感与桌布作对比
then you compared my heart and soul to a tablecloth.
我不是有意的
I didn't mean that.
就照顾我 好吗
Just look after me, yeah?
此事可以以吻封缄
It could be sealed with a kiss.
绝对要恭喜你了
Congratulations are definitely in order.
这个风险项目 你的公司...
This venture, your house...
我不太清楚你对布萨克先生说了什么
I'm not well informed as to what you said to Monsieur Boussac,
但他以前从未给任何个人投过这么多钱
but he has never before invested this much money in any one individual.
这是我的荣幸
Well, it's an honor.
你跟热龙说了吗
Have you told Lelong yet?
你要离开他 他一定会怒不可遏
He must be beside himself that you're leaving him.
还没说 但我会说的
Not yet. But I will.
但你得马上跟他说
But you must do it immediately.
克里斯汀 我们必须要完成所有的文件工作
Christian, we have to finish the paperwork.
雇佣裁缝 女裁缝 模特和员工
Hire the tailors, the seamstress. Hire the models, the staff.
还有选址 位置是非常重要的
Find the location. Location is crucial.
布萨克想要引人注目
Boussac wants something larger than life.
我想要的是更私密 更私人的
I was thinking something a little more intimate, more personal,
能够表达我专为少数女性提供服装的愿望
something that expresses my desire to dress a few women exquisitely.
当然可以 但经营规模还是要大
Of course. But it still needs to be on a grand scale.
布萨克希望的 不仅是只为少数女性提供服装
And Boussac will want something more than a few women dressed.
我相信你知道这一点
I'm sure you know that.
但我需要一点时间
But I will need a little time.
- 我不确定你是否知道 但... - 你妹妹从恐怖的集中营回来了
- I'm not sure whether you know, but-- - Your sister is back from the horrors.
好的 克里斯汀 这太好了 她怎么样
Yes. It's wonderful, Christian. How is she?
她在适应中 但需要一点时间
She's adjusting, but it will take a little time.
这是了不起的壮举啊
It's an amazing feat.
快回家尽你所能照顾凯瑟琳
Go home and take care of Catherine as best you can.
乔治斯 感谢
Thank you, Georges.
但作为你的商业伙伴
But as your business partner,
你应该知道布萨克不是一个很有耐心的人
you should know that Boussac is not a very patient man.
他有自己的时间表
He has his own timetable.
我明白 万分感谢
I understand. I am grateful.
别担心
Don't be concerned.
我很担心
Well, I am concerned.
是真的吗 她在这
Is it true? She's here?
是的 她在这
Yes, she's here.
谢谢
Thank you.
我必须见她
I have to see her.
埃尔维 她很虚弱 最好是等一等
Hervé, she's weak. It's best to wait.
不行 我必须和她谈谈
No. I must talk to her.
很快就可以了
And you will soon.
但今天不可以 她现在脑子还很迷糊
Not today. She's too confused.
她问起我了吗
Did she ask about me?
她患上了失忆症
She's suffering from amnesia.
抱歉 我必须见她
I'm sorry. I have to see her.
凯瑟琳
Catherine.
我以为我失去你了
I thought I'd lost you.
所有的一切听起来...
It all sounds--
现在说什么都很愚蠢
It's so foolish to say anything.
好了 让她休息吧
Okay, let's let her rest.
拜托
Please.
就一会儿
Just a moment.
她知道我在这
She knows I'm here.
我以为我失去你了
I thought I'd lost you.
听着 接下来的72小时内我们都不能上街
Look, we can't be on the streets for the next 72 hours.
别担心 风头过后我们马上就走
And don't worry. We'll leave immediately after that.
天黑后 我们会偷偷送走让
We will sneak out Jean after it is dark,
然后我们都会离开
and then we will all leave.
我明天再来
I'll come back tomorrow.
好吗
Okay?
凯瑟琳 握住我的手
Take my hand, Catherine.
告诉我另一个学生的名字
Tell me the name of the other student,
然后这一切就会停止
and all this will stop.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
- 喂 你好  - 迪奥先生 我有个好消息
- Yes? Hello. - I have good news, Monsieur Dior.
请原谅我 你是哪位
Forgive me. Who is this?
你的命运在呼叫你
This is your destiny calling.
我已经为你的新工作室 找到了一个完美的地点
I have identified the perfect location for your new atelier.
稍后乔治斯维格鲁会给你打电话约个时间
Georges Vigouroux will call you later and set up an appointment
去看工作室的位置
to see the location for the atelier.
布萨克先生 乔治斯知道我需要一 两天的时间
Oh, Mr. Boussac. Georges knows I need another day or two.
迪奥先生
Monsieur Dior,
我坚定不移地想把你的构想变成现实
I am unflinching in my desire to turn your vision into a reality,
但你必须做好应做的事
but you have to do your part.
毕竟这是一门生意
This is a business, after all.
是的 我知道 还有相信我 我真的很感激你
Yes, I know. And believe me, I'm very grateful.
很好 我该说的都说了
Good. Then all that needed to be said already has been.
迪奥 战争即将结束
War is ending, Monsieur Dior.
是时候开始新生活了
It's time for life to begin anew.
能让我感到希望是很罕见的
You know, it's unusual for me to feel hopeful.
但不知怎么地 你做到了
And yet, somehow, you made that happen.
你有韦特海默兄弟的消息吗
Have you heard from the Wertheimers?
- 还没 - 太可笑了
- Not yet. - This is ridiculous.
我要毁了他们
I'm going to ruin them.
有件事你需要明白
You need to understand something.
- 过去的事不会回头给我们造成困扰 - 你在说什么
- Nothing can come back to haunt us. - What are you talking about?
如果你要和韦特海默兄弟开战
If you are going to go to war with the Wertheimers,
所有的秘密就会公之于众
then all the skeletons are going to come out of the closet.
你还有什么是没告诉我的吗
Now, is there anything you haven't told me?
没有...什么也没有
No. No. There is nothing.
有什么秘密是我不知道的吗
Any secrets that I don't know about?
别再问同样的问题了
Stop asking the same question.
如果你今天不给他们打电话要求回复 我会打给他们的
If you don't call them today and demand a reply, I will!
天啊 听起来你遇到麻烦了
Oh, dear. Sounds like you're in trouble.
艾尔莎 不要说我
Don't start, Elsa.
我生命中所拥有的一切都是我挣来的
All the things I have in life, I earned them.
我白手起家建立了香奈儿公司
I built the House of Chanel from nothing.
香奈儿5号香水是我发明的 是我给他们的
And Chanel No. 5, I invented it. I brought it to them.
现在他们以为偷了我的东西就能逃脱惩罚
And now they think they can get away with stealing it from me.
是谁想从你这偷走它
Who wants to steal it from you?
皮埃尔韦特海默和他那愚蠢的弟弟保罗
Pierre Wertheimer and his stupid brother Paul.
他们逃不掉的 我会得到我应得的
They aren't gonna get away with it. I will get what I'm owed.
很好 我完全赞成人们得到他们应得的
Good. I'm all in favor of people getting what they're owed.
包括我自己
Myself included.
看来今晚的派对会很不错
Looks like it's going to be quite a good party tonight.
你收到邀请函了吗
Did you get your invitation?
我的邀请函 没有 为什么这么问
My invitation? No. Why?
酒店的所有客人都收到邀请函了 前台给了我一个
All the hotel guests are invited. I got given one at the front desk.
我们不去参加派对
We're not going to the party.
为什么不去  让我们来看看上面写了什么 好吗
Why not? Let's see what it says, shall we?
“尊敬的客人和未来的朋友...”
"Distinguished guests and future friends"--
挺贴心的 有点受宠若惊
That's quite sweet. Kind of flattering.
“这么多年过去了 我们都没什么值得庆祝的事”
"After so many years with nothing to celebrate"--
确实如此
True.
“我们诚挚地邀请您 与我们一同为生活举杯
"You are cordially invited to come and raise a glass to life with us
时间是今天下午4点到午夜的任何时刻”
today anytime from 4:00 p.m. to midnight."
我们不认识这些人
We don't know these people.
事实上 我认为你认识他们
Actually, I think you do.
什么
What?
“期待与您相识
"Looking forward to making your acquaintance,
皮埃尔韦特海默夫妇”
Mr. and Mrs. Pierre Wertheimer."
太搞笑了
Very funny.
这里就是这么写的
That's what it says here.
这可不是巧合
That is not a coincidence.
这就是他没有回应的原因
That's why he hasn't responded.
你看 他在玩游戏 但这是场战争
You see, he's playing games, but this is war.
我需要指引
I need guidance.
事情有点不太对劲
Something's not right.
就是...凯瑟琳不在了
It's just... Catherine is gone.
我知道她会变 但却变得让人认不出了
I knew she would be changed, but she's unrecognizable.
- 谁认不出  - 我
- To whom? - To me.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
我一直在想象她一定经历过什么样的事
I keep imagining the things she must have gone through,
然后...
and...
我在脑海中看到的场景是那么的...
the scenarios that I see in my mind are so--
残忍 那么的阴冷
They're merciless and so bleak.
你觉得她在怪你吗
Do you feel she blames you?
我在怪我自己
I blame me.
我离开的话 你会更安全
It's safer for you if I leave.
而且我可以和其他学生待在一起
And I can stay with the other students.
对大家来说 这样更安全
It's safer for all of us.
根据我们目前的报告可确定
Our reports now confirm that
会在巴拉德射击场处决五名学生
all five students will be executed at the Balard shooting range.
凯瑟琳 我需要你去传些消息 好吗
Catherine, I need you to deliver some messages, okay?
请不要让她去
Please don't send her.
我们必须试一试
We have to try.
我明白
I understand.
带我去见凯瑟琳
Bring me to Catherine.
谢谢
Thank you.
进入派对后 由我来带头 好吗
When we get inside the party, let me take the lead.
我不在乎这个
I don't care.
你想跟皮埃尔谈多久都行 他已经结婚了
You can talk to Pierre as much as you want. He's married.
我在找未婚人士
I'm looking for someone more available.
你好
Hello.
想喝酒吗
Want a drink?
不想吗
No?
好吧 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
如果有人问起我们是怎么认识的
And if anyone asks how you and I know each other,
就告诉他们我们是老朋友
just tell them we're old friends.
战争前就认识了
From before the war.
无论你做什么 都不要提及任何尤为复杂的话题
Whatever you do, don't mention any of the more complicated issues.
不要提像马德里那样复杂的话题
No complicated issues like Madrid.
- 你懂我的意思 对吧  - 我当然懂
- You know what I mean, right? - Yes, I certainly do.
我只是来看望我一生中最亲密的朋友
I'm just here visiting one of my dearest friends in life.
整件事就是这样
That's all there is to it.
名字
Name?
你认识我 请让开
You know me. Please step aside.
小姐 很抱歉 我们需要确认名单上的所有名字
I do apologize, mademoiselle. We need to confirm all names on the list.
可可香奈儿
Coco Chanel.
小姐 对不起 名单上没有可可香奈儿
I'm sorry, mademoiselle. There is no Coco Chanel on the list.
我有邀请函
I have mine.
“艾尔莎隆巴尔迪小姐”
"Miss Elsa Lombardi."
好的 你的名字就在这里
Yes. Your name is right here.
- 今晚很高兴见到你 - 我也是
- So good to see you this evening. - You too.
- 请这边走 - 谢谢
- Please. Right this way. - Thank you.
那她呢 不是所有的客人都被邀请了吗
Well, what about her? Aren't all the hotel guests invited?
几乎所有的客人
Almost all.
韦特海默先生亲自核准了客人名单
Mr. Wertheimer personally approved the guest list.
我相信只是弄混了或其它什么原因
Well, I'm sure it's just been some sort of mix-up or something.
亲爱的 我们里面见
I'll see you in there, darling.
我无法接受这种做法 我要进去
This isn't acceptable. I'm going in.
不行
No.
你不能进去 你没有邀请函
Not you. You don't have an invitation.
听我说
Now, look here.
小姐 拜托了
Please, mademoiselle.
我不想叫保安过来
I don't want to have to call security.
别碰我 你这个小小的令人讨厌的野蛮人
Don't you touch me, you tiny, little beast of a man.
小姐 这是个私人派对
Mademoiselle, this is a private party.
欢迎你和其他未被邀请的客人一起进餐
You're welcome to dine with the other guests that weren't invited.
我会让你为此丢掉工作
I will have you fired for this.
那也值得
Worth it.
吃吧
Here you go.
给我 我来试一下
Here. I'll give it a try.
太可悲了
Pathetic.
各位 欢迎你们 我是皮埃尔韦特海默
Welcome, everyone. I am Pierre Wertheimer.
很高兴你们能参加此次派对
It is so good you are all here
一同庆祝世界繁荣与和平的新篇章
to celebrate the new chapter of prosperity and peace in our world.
请为所有聚集在这里的人举杯
Please raise a glass to all of us who have gathered here.
干杯
Cheers.
皮埃尔
Pierre.
你不能来参加我的派对真是太遗憾了
It's a shame you couldn't come to my party.
你进去遇到麻烦了吗
Did you have trouble getting in?
你说的是你才离开的那个超棒的派对
You mean the fabulous party you just left
这样你就可以过来跟我说话了
so that you could come talk to me?
就是那个派对 我抱歉没邀请你
Yes, that one. I apologize for your lack of invitation.
我和我弟弟收到你寄来的信件了
So my brother and I got your little letter.
就是威胁要起诉我们的信
The one threatening to sue us.
表达十分清晰 接近专业水平
Quite articulate actually. Almost professional.
我会确保你把欠我的还给我
I'll make sure you give me what you owe me.
好吧 但我不这么认为
Yeah, I think not.
你援用雅利安人法逼我们出局的小把戏
That little stunt you pulled invoking the Aryan laws to force us out.
我们可以随时按下按钮
We can push the button anytime
将这个消息传播出去
on spreading the word about that.
更别提你住在丽兹的多少个晚上
Not to mention your many nights at the Ritz
都用来招待那些踢正步的小丑了
spent entertaining those goose-stepping clowns.
我听够了
I've heard enough.
我跟你说话时别走开
Don't walk away from me when I'm talking to you.
那就别说话
Then stop talking.
我要起诉你
I'm suing you.
你已经靠我的名字和香水发了财
You've made a fortune out of my name and fragrance.
我们一起做生意二十年了
Twenty years we've been doing business together,
现在你觉得你能偷走我的东西吗
and now you think you can steal from me?
我们法庭上见
I'll see you in court.
你和你那可怜的弟弟
You and your pathetic brother.
这事永远不会发生 我们不会允许的
That will never happen. We won't allow it.
你欠我的 你这个该死的白痴
You owe me, you fucking idiot!
我们之前达成了协议 你 我和我弟弟一起达成的很好的协议
We made a deal. You, me and my brother. A good one.
你知道你会惹上什么麻烦 而我们也遵守了协议
You knew what you were getting into, and we kept our end of the bargain.
你分到了属于你的10% 我不知道你为什么总是抱怨
You got your 10%. I don't know why you keep complaining about it.
- 因为你骗了我 - 通过支持你 通过相信你
- Because you tricked me! - By backing you? Believing in you?
说正经的
Get serious.
事实上 你连自己公司的潜力都没看到
The truth is, you couldn't even see the potential of your own business.
当然了 现在你把这都归功于自己
Sure, you take credit for it now,
但那时你却很乐意将其出售
but back then you were more than happy to pass it off
这样你就可以和你那些白痴的朋友聚会了
so you could go party with your idiot friends.
骗子 你这个肮脏的 令人讨厌的骗子
Liar. You dirty, stinking liar!
承认吧...
Admit it. Admit it.
你把公司给了一对犹太人 是因为你知道我们能让你赚大钱
You gave your business to a pair of Jews because you knew we would make you rich.
你们这些人只擅长做这个
That's all you people are good at.
你刚才说什么
What did you just say?
你听到我说的了
You heard me.
钱...你们只会赚钱
Money, money, money. All you are is money.
不好意思
Excuse me.
谈话还没结束
This conversation isn't over.
皮埃尔 你从未懂我 你永远都不会
You never understood me, Pierre, and you never will.
好好享受你的派对吧
Enjoy your party.
你回来了
You are returned.
你的身体在这里
Your body is here.
但你的灵魂在别处
But your spirit is elsewhere.
- 我不想再继续了 - 我之前也这样觉得 但之后事情就发生了
- I don't think I want to continue. - That's how I felt. And then it happened.
德拉哈耶夫人在幻象中看到你了
Madame Delahaye saw you in a vision.
- 她看到我了  - 是的
- She saw me? - Yes.
她知道你会回来
She knew that you would return.
这是不可能的
It's not possible.
这样做没意义 对任何事都没意义
There is no meaning to this, to any of it.
我现在看到你在那里的画面了
I see you there now.
你很痛苦
You are in so much pain.
每个人都很痛苦
Everyone was suffering.
但另外还有个人和你在一起
But there's someone else with you.
他们是单独折磨我们的
They tortured us alone.
我在浴室看到的可不是这样
That's not what I see in the bathroom.
你对那个浴室知道些什么
What do you know about that bathroom?
不 你握住了对方的手
No. You took their hand.
握住我的手
Take my hand.
那个人帮你活了下来
They helped you survive.
你独自一人在这
Here you are alone.
- 但那里... - 够了
- But there-- - That's enough.
你哥哥把你带到我身边
Your brother has brought you to me
这样我也许 能给你那颗烦恼的心带来些许慰藉
so that I might bring some solace to a troubled heart.
当时有人跟你在一起 你握住了对方的手
There was someone with you. You took their hand.
克里斯汀
Christian.
滚出去
Get out of here.
- 我为你经历的一切感到抱歉 - 德拉哈耶夫人 走
- I'm so sorry for what you went through... - Come, Madame Delahaye.
- 亲爱的 - 下次再说 非常感谢
- ...my dear - Another time. And thank you so much.
克里斯汀 带她离开这里
Christian, get her out of here.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
索菲
Sophie.
Sophie!
先生
Monsieur?
迪奥先生说他不来了吗  我们计划去看房产的
Did Monsieur Dior say he's not coming? We are scheduled to visit properties.
没有说
I don't believe so.
- 取消预约 - 好的 先生
- Cancel the appointment. - All right, monsieur.
布萨克先生会不高兴的
Monsieur Boussac will not be pleased.
凯瑟琳
Catherine.
她只是想帮你 我们都只是想帮你
She was just trying to help you. We all just want to help you.
帮我
Help me?
你们帮不了我
You cannot help me.
但你回家了
But you're home.
你现在和我们在这里 你必须和我们在这里
You're here now with us. You have to be here with us.
就让我帮你吧
Just let me help you.
是我的错 让的遭遇
It's my fault, what happened to Jean.
我就不该让他离开这间公寓
I should never have asked him to leave this apartment.
他在这里很安全
He was safe here.
你得原谅自己 当时那种情况 他不可能留在这
You must forgive yourself. It was an impossible situation.
先生 小姐
Monsieur? Mademoiselle?
我之前想来看你 我听说你的情况不太好
I wanted to come see you. I heard you were not doing well.
- 我之前打过电话 - 不行
- I called earlier. - No.
- 我想跟你谈谈 - 不行 不见客
- I wanted to speak to you. - No. No visitors.
年轻人 现在不是时候 拜托
It's not a good time, young man. Please.
我之前见过你
I've seen your face before.
我是怎么认识你的
How do I know you?
我是让的朋友 我听说你回家了
I was a friend of Jean. I heard that you were home.
请帮个忙 跟我走一趟好吗
Would you do me the favor of coming with me, please?
我有东西要给你看
There is something I need to show you.
凯瑟琳 你身体不好
Catherine, you are in no condition.
先生 这很重要
Sir, I think it's important.
当然可以
Of course.
就在这里
It's just over here.
这就是他们所在的地方
This is where they are.
他们
They?
是的 让和其他人
Yes, Jean and the others.
我们一共有六个人
There were six of us total.
我们在我祖母的房子里 安装了一台小型印刷机
We set up a small printing press in my grandmother's house
然后我们就开始分发反纳粹的传单
and started distributing anti-Nazi leaflets.
起初 这么做似乎没什么影响
In the beginning, it seemed like it wouldn't matter.
但随着影响力日渐增大 抵抗军不断壮大
But it grew. The Resistance grew.
便引起了纳粹敌对势力的注意
And then it caught the attention of the Nazi counterparts.
当我的五个朋友都被纳粹抓走时
When all five of my friends were taken by the Nazis,
我确信下一个会是我
I thought for sure I would be next.
但却没人来找我
But then no one came for me.
第二天 我是安全的
And the next day, I was safe.
我的家人是安全的
And my family was safe.
之后的那天我们也是如此
And the day after that too.
那时我就知道 我的朋友们不会说出我的名字
And that's when I knew my friends would not name me.
我的朋友没有供出我 你也没有
My friends did not break, and you did not break.
我不知道你是如何 在重重折磨下保持缄默的
I do not know how you kept silent through all the torture.
我是来感谢你的
I'm here to say thank you.
我欠你一条命
I owe you my life.
你给了我第二次重新生活的机会
You gave me a second chance to live again.
你准备好了我就送你回家
I will take you home when you are ready.
我现在想起来了
I remember now.
我现在能想起来了
I can remember now.
在集中营里 人们不敢相信 我是有多勇敢才能在折磨中活下来
At the camp people couldn't believe how brave I was to survive the torture.
但不是因为勇敢我才没有说出来
But it wasn't bravery that kept me from talking.
不是胆量
It wasn't courage.
我现在想起来了
I remember now.
是因为你 克里斯汀
It was you, Christian.
没事的
It's okay.
我太累了
I'm so tired.
我希望他们能杀了我
I wish they would kill me.
死掉并不难
Dying is easy.
只有你知道自己该怎么做
Only you know what you should do.
你听见我说话吗 你在跟谁说话
Do you hear me? Who are you talking to?
我对你没什么可说的
I have nothing to say to you!
抓住她...
Get her! Get her!
不要
No!
抱歉打扰你了
Sorry to bother you.
不会 克里斯汀
No bother, Christian.
我只是...我想告诉你 很抱歉我爽约了
I just-- I wanted to tell you I'm sorry for missing our meeting,
还有我明天和以后的每一天都会在那
and I will be there tomorrow and every day thereafter.
- 我得相信你能靠得住 - 我不会让你失望的
- I need to be able to count on you. - I won't let you down.
我们会一起创造出伟大的东西 你 我和布萨克
We'll make something great together. You, me and Boussac.
这是很难得的
It's rare, you know.
什么东西
What is?
获得人生的第二次机会
To get a second chance in life.
第二次机会
Second chance?
是的 我得到了第二次机会
Yes. I have been given a second chance.
我觉得我们都得到了
I think we all have.
艾尔莎 去你自己的房间
Find your own room, Elsa.
我没心情听你胡扯
I'm not in the mood for your bullshit.
天啊
For Christ's sake.
- 你想干吗  - 你说得很对
- What do you want? - You're absolutely right.
我从未懂你
I've never understood you.
- 皮埃尔 - 但我想了解你
- Pierre. - But I want to.
今晚
Tonight.
给我跪下
Get on your knees.
可可 别这样
Coco, please.
不是我 是我弟弟干的
It's not me. It's my brother.
那就乖乖听话
So then be a good boy.
把我的钱给我
And pay me my fucking money.
字幕翻译:王国萱